Robert Hillyer Papers
Robert Hillyer Papers
- Literary correspondence
  - Bynner, Witter, 1939; 1942,; 1946-1949,; 1952-1961; 31 Letters (Box 1)
    22 Nov. 1953 - TLS Congratulates Hillyer on marriage.
    24 Sept. 1954 - TLS Discusses nomination of Oliver St. John Gogarty for nomination for Academy Award and contains interesting story concerning earlier failure to win Pulitzer Prize allegedly because of his supposed affluence.
    20 Jan. 1956 - TLS
    17 Feb. 1956 - TLS
    12 Nov. 1957 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's The Relic And Other Poems and comments on his style.
    11 Mar. 1958 - TLS Requests picture.
    7 Apr. 1958 - Signed Note.
    6 Nov. 1958 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's lecture on Robert Burns.
    12 Nov. 1958 - TLS Inquires about Royall H. Snow.
    5 Oct. 1959 - TLS Writes of Hillyer's poem "Assembling The Family" and mentions current project of Bynner.
    10 Aug. 1960 - TLS Comments on Ezra Pound.
    8 Nov. 1960 - TLS Comments on Bynner's book New Poems 1960.
    5 Dec. 1960 - TLS Encloses letter from Ellery Larsson containing lengthy comments about Hillyer.
    10 Dec. 1960 - TLS Discusses Santa Fe as retirement spot.
    2 May 1961 - TLS Mentions vote in Academy of Arts and Letters.
    15 May 1961 - TLS
    21 Jun. 1961 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's Collected Poems and discusses Bynner's health.
    25 Sept. 1961 - TLS
    28 Nov. 1961 - TLS Further comments on health and Collected Poems.
    12 Dec. 1961 - TLS Agrees to recommend Hillyer for Academy Award if Hillyer resigns from Academy.
    4 Jan. 1961 - Letter of condolence to Mrs. Hillyer.
  - Cane, Melville, 1952; 1958; 3 Letters (Box 1)
    1 Dec. 1952 - ALS Sends copy of "Woodberry's" letter praising Hillyer and comments on current activities of Cane.
    3 Feb. 1958 - ALS Discusses current activities and encloses an inscribed typed copy of his poem "Enchanted Snow."
    28 Jun. 1958 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's The Coming Forth By Day.
  - Canfield, Cass, 1956; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    26 Oct. 1956 - TLS Sends advance copy of Millay collection about to be published.
  - Caras, Dean, 1961; 1 Note (Box 1)
    29 Nov. 1961 - Signed Note. Mentions plan to produce Hillyer's play The Masquerade.
  - Carman, Bliss, 1923; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    30 Sept. 1923 - ALS Requests permission to use Hillyer's "Scarlatti Passepied" and selections from his "Sonnet Sequence" in new edition of Oxford Book of American Verse.
  - Caughey, Elford, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    27 Sept. 1949 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's articles on Pound and poem "The Death of Captain Nemo."
  - Chamberlin, Frederick, 1922-1924; 10 Letters, 1 Card (Box 1)
    13 Feb. 1922 - TLS Discusses author's The Private Character of Queen Elizabeth.
    6 Mar. 1922 - ALS Encloses a clipping reviewing the author's book.
    2 May 1922 - TLS Further comments on reviews author's book received on both sides of Atlantic.
    1923 - Card with holograph greeting wishes Happy New Year.
    Apr. 1923 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's translations of Danish lyric poets and comments on author's new book, The Sayings of Queen Elizabeth.
    8 May 1923 - ALS Further comments on The Sayings of Queen Elizabeth.
    20 Sept. 1923 - TLS Discusses the possible effects of a Hillyer review of The Sayings of Queen Elizabeth.
    23 Oct. 1923 - ALS Urgently requests that Hillyer delay release of his review of The Sayings of Queen Elizabeth.
    16 Nov. 1923 - Encloses clippings and typed copies of reviews of The Sayings of Queen Elizabeth.
    8 Feb. 1924 - TLS Thanks for review of author's work in The Freeman, and praises Hillyer's writing style.
    26 Mar. 1924 - ALS
  - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1935; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    5 Jan. 1935 - ALS
  - Cheever, John, 1959; 2 Letters (Box 1)
    4 Jan. 1959 - TLS Refers to Hillyer's essay in The New York Times of Jan. 4, 1959 mentioning author's The Wapshot Chronicle.
    15 Jan. 1959 - TLS
  - Chubb, T. C., 1959; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    31 Mar. 1959 - TLS Discusses Bermuda as a possible retirement spot for Hillyer.
  - Chute, Marchette, 1961; 1 Note (Box 1)
    2 Apr. 1961 - AS Writes concerning Hillyer's review of Jesus of Israel.
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1949; 1961; 2 Letters (Box 1)
    22 Jun. 1949 - ALS Requests Hillyer's definition of democracy for Symposium being organized by Clemens.
    16 Dec. 1961 - ALS Concerns facsimile of President John F. Kennedy's tribute to Mark Twain.
  - Coblentz, Stanton, 1949; 3 Letters (Box 1)
    3 Jun. 1949 - TLS Compliments Hillyer on his article on poetry in the Spring number of The Lyric and encloses leaflet opposing Ezra Pound published by The League For Sanity In Poetry.
    18 Jun. 1949 - TLS Strongly praises Hillyer's article on Pound in the Saturday Review of Literature.
    5 Jul. 1949 - TLS Comments on and quotes from review of William Carlos Williams concerning Pound; encloses letter to Luther Evans protesting appointment of Williams as consultant in poetry and article entitled "The Rise of The Anti-Poet."
  - Coffin, Robert P. Tristram, 1936; 1 Letter (Box 1)
    8 Jul. 1936 - ALS Praises Hillyer's work and character.
  - Colony, Horatio, 1936; 1958; 2 Letters (Box 1)
    16 Mar. 1936 - ALS Concerns Colony's A Brook of Leaves.
    24 Apr. 1958 - ALS Notes Colony's "Young Malatesta" and laments on the present state of poetry.
  - Colum, Mary, 1938; 1947; 4 Letters (Box 1)
    26 Apr. 1938 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's First Principles of Verse and describes current activities of the author in organizing poetry groups.
    10 Mar. 1947 - TLS Discusses some of Colum's poetry.
    12 Apr. 1947 - TLS Contains personal news.
    24 Feb. [1947] - TLS Discusses Hillyer's review of Colum's poetry.
  - Colum, Padraic, 1921; 1949; 2 Letters (Box 1)
    4 Oct. 1921 - ALS Concerns Hillyer's poetry.
    22 May 1949 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's "Ode To Aphrodite" and contemporary poetry.
  - Copeland, Charles T., 1923; 1928-1930,; 1932,; 1935,; 1937-1941,; 1944; 35 Letters, 2 Cards (Box 1)
    4 May 1923 - TLS
    5 Apr. 1928 - TLS Mentions Walter D. Edmonds.
    20 Apr. 1928 - TLS
    14 Nov. 1928 - TLS Requests Hillyer's phone number.
    16 Nov. 1928 - TLS
    30 Apr. 1929 - TLS
    2 Feb. 1930 - TLS
    3 May 1930 - TLS
    13 Nov. 1930 - ALS
    17 Dec. 1932 - ALS Writes of Walter D. Edmonds and of Hillyer's novel Riverhead.
    7 Sept. 1935 - TLS
    5 Mar. 1937 - TLS Discusses a Hillyer poem in The Atlantic.
    9 May 1937 - TLS Refers to Hillyer's "Letter to Charles Townsend Copeland."
    17 Jul. 1937 - TLS Encloses copy of letter from D. Moffat.
    6 Sept. 1937 - TLS Comments further on "Letter to Charles Townsend Copeland."
    18 Jan. 1938 - TLS Compliments Hillyer on A Letter To Robert Frost And Others.
    10 Feb. 1938 -
    16 Feb. 1938 - TLS
    28 Apr. 1938 - TLS
    16 May 1938 - TLS Mentions A Letter to Robert Frost and Others with addenda.
    23 Jul. 1938 - TLS Mentions compliment to Hillyer from friend of Copeland.
    21 Aug. 1938 - TLS More remarks about A Letter to Robert Frost and Others.
    24 Aug. 1938 - TLS Encloses anecdote about John Barrymore.
    7 Sept. 1938 - TLS Mentions Copeland's health.
    19 Sept. 1938 - TLS Further mention of health.
    6 Oct. 1938 - TLS
    31 Dec. 1939 - TLS with addenda.
    15 Jan. 1940 - ALS Makes date to get professional advice from Hillyer
    26 Jun. 1940 - Signed Card. Compliments Hillyer on poem in The Atlantic.
    16 May 1940 - TLS Discusses The Collected Verse of Robert Hillyer.
    13 Oct. 1940 - TLS Inquires about Hillyer's condition.
    26 Oct. 1940 - TLS Discusses the condition of Frank Hersey.
    22 Max. 1941 - TLS Reminds Hillyer of luncheon date.
    30 Jul. 1941 - TLS Comments on present condition of Copeland.
    3 Aug. 1941 - TLS Inquires into Hillyer's present work.
    30 Aug. 1941 - ALS Inquires into attitudes of Hillyer and other Harvard men toward war situation.
    18 Dec. 1944 - ALS Comments on Hillyer's decision to give up Boylston Professorship and devote all time to writing.
  - Cozzens, James Gould, 1949-1950; 1955,; 1960-1961; 6 Letters (Box 1)
    5 May 1949 - TLS
    10 Feb. 1950 - TLS Detailed appreciation of The Death of Captain Nemo and compliments Hillyer on article about Pound.
    10 Aug. 1955 - TLS
    7 Nov. 1960 - TLS Discusses In Pursuit of Poetry.
    12 Nov. 1960 - TLS Discusses possibility of giving quote for Hillyer's book.
    26 Dec. 1961 - TLS Condolences to Mrs. Hillyer.
  - Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1938; 1961; 4 Letters) (Box 1)
    14 Nov. 1938 - TLS Requests details about proposed speaking engagement at Harvard before the Morris Gray Fund audience.
    20 Nov. 1938 - TLS States certain conditions necessary for his acceptance of the mentioned speaking engagement.
    16 Dec. 1938 - TLS
    26 Dec. 1961 - TLS Encloses correct copy of poem by author and gives Hillyer permission to use it for unidentified project.
  - Damon, S(amuel) Foster, 1924-1928; 1932,; 1937,; 1947,; 1957-1959,; 1961-1962; 34 Letters (Box 2)
    24 Jun. 1924 - TLS Talks about author's work William Blake - His Philosophy and Symbols and about "Margery" mediumship.
    6 Jul. 1924 - ALS Discusses American edition of author's work on Blake and Hillyer's Alchemy.
    22 Jul. 1924 - ALS Further comments on Blake and discussion of possible radio program for poetry.
    2 Aug. 1924 - ALS Mentions reappointments at Harvard.
    13 Aug. 1924 - ALS Deals with spiritualism and the "Margery" mediumship.
    30 Aug. 1924 - ALS Concerns mediumship and gives many details of Damon's attitude towards same.
    5 Jun. 1925 - ALS Further details the "Margery" mediumship and describes a seance.
    26 Jun. 1925 - ALS Discusses the seance at length and describes an incident in the "Margery" mediumship
    2 July 1925 - ALS Describes new developments in the "Margery" mediumship in detail and quotes from Walter the ghost
    5 Jul. 1925 - ALS Explains the incidents of the "Margery" mediumship as results of strong hypnotic suggestion, automatism and amnesia.
    8 Jul. 1925 - TLS Discusses the solution of "Margery" incidents with remarks about the current literary activity of the author.
    17 Jul. 1925 - ALS with Enclosures. Explains the entire "Margery" mediumship story and pieces together all details in an effort to give a complete resolution of the Problem. Supporting evidence is supplied. Enclosures as follows: (1) Letter from Grant H. Code explaining his hypotheses on "Margery" incidents and of a private interview with Walter the ghost; (2) Transcript of seance of 29 June 1925 signed by participants; (3) Transcript of seance of 30 June 1925 signed by participants; (4) Letter from Dr. Crandon concerning the reports of "Margery" seances and his reaction to the findings.
    29 Aug. 1925 - ALS Describes author's personal difficulties
    22 Jan. 1926 - ALS Seeks Hillyer's opinion on Astrolabe as a title for a book of author's poems, and comments on John Drinkwater.
    25 Sept. 1926 - ALS Amusingly describes beginning of college year and new lodgings.
    21 Nov. 1926 - ALS Discusses Damon's current literary activity especially two poems, "Bridge" and "Commentary On John X."
    1926 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for a gift of pajamas and amusingly describes them.
    15 Jan. 1927 - ALS Concerns author's book of poems, Astrolabe.
    8 Feb. 1927 - ALS Contains new details of investigation of "Margery" mediumship.
    23 Feb. 1927 - ALS Describes author's intention to move to Brown University
    23 Mar. 1927 - TLS Details scandals following the "Margery" mediumship and comments on Sinclair Lewis' Elmer Gantry.
    21 May 1927 - ALS
    1927 - ALS Describes author's life and attitudes at Brown University.
    31 Oct. 1927 - TLS
    14 Oct. 1928 - ALS Mentions James Agee and discusses Damon's school year activities.
    1 Oct. 1932 - TLS Amusingly describes laudatory reaction to Hillyer's novel Riverhead.
    11 Nov. 1937 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's A Letter to Robert Frost And Others.
    11 Dec. 1947 - TLS Discusses current activity.
    7 Nov. 1957 - TLS
    31 Oct. 1958 - TLS Mentions Damon's work on Blake.
    17 Feb. 1959 - TLS Mentions Grant Code in detail and trip to New York.
    14 Apr. 1959 - TLS Talks of Hillyer's The Relic And Other Poems.
    16 Dec. 1961 - TLS Talks of work on Dictionary of Blake's Symbols.
    3 Jan. 1962 - ALS Condolences to Mrs. Hillyer.
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1943; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    14 Apr. 1943 - TLS with holograph addenda. Discusses the possibility of setting one of Hillyer's poems to music.
  - Davidson, Gustav, 1949; 2 Notes (Box 2)
    18 Jun. 1949 - Signed Note. Encloses letter supporting Hillyer's stand on Pound.
    22 Jul. 1949 - Signed Note. Encloses copy of night letter sent to Javits in support of Hillyer's stand in Library of Congress controversy.
  - Decker, Clarence, 1957; 13 Letters (Box 2)
    9 Sept. 1957 - TLS Discusses a "Hillyer feature" for The Literary Review mentioning several possible contributors and asking Hillyer's recommendations for articles concerning publishing.
    12 Sept. 1957 - TLS Discusses unpublished correspondence to be used in Hillyer feature, accepts "four decades approach" to feature and emphasizes use to be made of Hillyer reminiscence; copy of letter to Winfield Scott enclosed.
    17 Sept. 1957 - TLS Mentions Hillyer letters to Thomas H. Johnson to be included in article under discussion and mentions two articles by Oliver St. John Gogarty to be published in The Literary Review.
    20 Sept. 1957 - TLS Mentions round-up feature on Gogarty and asks Hillyer to do article; encloses copy of letter to Winfield Scott and Gogarty.
    23 Sept. 1957 - TLS Discusses death of Gogarty and mentions article about Hillyer.
    26 Sept. 1957 - TLS Sets deadline for Hillyer article; encloses copy of letter to Winfield Scott.
    14 Oct. 1957 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's eulogy of Gogarty.
    15 Oct. 1957 - TLS Mentions passage in Hillyer letter on Robert Fitzgerald.
    6 Nov. 1957 - TLS Names items to be included in feature on Hillyer.
    22 Nov. 1957 - TLS Reports on progress of Hillyer feature and mentions use of unpublished Hillyer poems.
    3 Dec. 1957 - TLS Discusses progress of Hillyer feature.
    6 Dec. 1957 - TLS Names poems to be included in article on Hillyer.
    12 Dec. 1957 - TLS Mentions Poetry Society of America dinner and encloses copies of letters to Alfred A. Knopf and Winfield Scott.
  - Dello Joio, Norman, 1958; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    7 May 1958 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for sending poems to be set to music.
  - Devoto, Bernard, 1936-1937; undated; 4 Letters (Box 2)
    11 Sept. Undated - TLS Discusses the publication of a Hillyer poem in The Saturday Review of Literature, with comments regarding the magazine's change of policy.
    19 Apr. Undated - ALS
    14 Oct. 1936 - TLS Discusses the misprints in a Hillyer poem which appeared in The Saturday Review of Literature.
    11 Aug. 1937 - TLS Discusses the review of Hillyer's A Letter To Robert Frost And Others and the problems of New York reviewers.
  - Dodd, Lee Wilson, 1932; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    14 Nov. 1932 - ALS Discusses and analyzes Hillyer's novel Riverhead at length.
  - Dos Passos, John, 1921-1922; 1925,; 1927-1929,; 1931,; 1937-1938,; 1940-1941,; 1943-1944,; 1947-1949,; 1951-1961; 56 Letters, 14 Cards (Box 2)
    18 Jan. 1921 - ALS Concerns the review of Hillyer's Alchemy; autographed review enclosed.
    3 Jul. 1921 - ALS Describes reaction to Venice.
    14 Nov. 1921 - ALS Notes observations on Persia.
    20 Nov. 1921 - ALS Discusses Dos Passos' projects.
    10 Jan. 1922 - ALS Discusses present philosophical condition of Dos Passos.
    31 Oct. 1922 - ALS Mentions the completion of a book.
    20 Jul. 1925 - ALS Discusses personal state of health.
    11 Sept. 1925 - ALS Writes about Manhattan Transfer.
    27 Mar. 1927 - ALS Congratulations on the birth of Hillyer's son.
    17 May 1927 - ALS
    31 May 1927 - Signed Card.
    23 Jul. 1928 - Signed Card. Describes Finland.
    25 Apr. 1928 - ALS Discusses David Gordon case concerning imprisonment for writing "un-American" poetry, and encloses a mimeographed broadside asking for protest against this. copy of poem enclosed.
    10 Jan. 1929 - ALS Deals with author's play Airways, Inc. which opened February 19, 1928.
    22 Dec. 1931 - Signed Card.
    9 Mar. 1937 - ALS
    10 Sept. 1938 - ALS Mentions temper of Europe.
    29 Jul. 1940 - Signed Card. Talks of a current Dos Passos' project.
    2 Apr. 1941 - Signed Card.
    20 May 1941 - Signed Card.
    12 Aug. 1941 - Signed Card.
    8 Sept. 1941 - ALS
    10 Dec. 1941 - ALS
    24 Feb. 1943 - ALS Mentions current literary activity of author.
    24 Mar. 1943 - ALS Discusses author's book Number One humorously.
    23 Dec. 1943 - ALS Requests loan of hundred dollars.
    26 Dec. 1943 - ALS Contains an essay of sorts on overdrafting an account.
    21 Jan. 1944 - ALS Refers to State Of The Nation.
    1944 - Signed Card. Thanks Hillyer for loan.
    16 Mar. 1944 - ALS Returns loan and inquires about trip Hillyer made.
    3 Apr. 1944 - ALS Writes of book State Of The Nation and of a book by Dos Passos' wife.
    3 Nov. 1944 - ALS Denies at length that the character "Savage" in State Of The Nation is a caricature of Hillyer.
    1944 - ALS Discusses further crisis related to alleged caricature of Hillyer.
    19 Sept. 1947 - ALS
    13 Jan. 1948 - ALS Writes of eye trouble.
    9 Sept. 1948 - Signed Card.
    28 Jun. 1948 - Signed Card.
    22 Aug. 1949 - (Marriage announcement of Dos Passos to Mrs. Elizabeth Holdridge.)
    24 Oct. 1949 - Signed Card.
    11 Jul. 1951 - ALS with enclosure.
    29 Feb. 1952 - ALS Writes about Hillyer's Suburb By The Sea.
    30 Oct. 1953 - ALS
    1953 - ALS
    Undated - Signed Card.
    24 Feb. 1954 - ALS Discusses new book by Dos Passos.
    17 Apr. 1954 - ALS Discusses projected visit by Hillyer.
    17 Jul. 1954 - ALS Remarks about Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo and Suburb By The Sea.
    19 Mar. 1955 - ALS Details of Hillyer's projected visit.
    28 Mar. 1955 - ALS
    29 Apr. 1955 - ALS
    21 May 1955 - ALS Mentions interest in Essenes.
    15 Jun. 1955 - ALS
    10 Jan. 1956 - Signed Card.
    29 Apr. 1956 - ALS Talks of book The Theme Is Freedom.
    11 Jun. 1956 - ALS Discusses title to use for book The Theme Is Freedom.
    15 Aug. 1956 - Signed Card.
    25 Aug. 1957 - ALS Notes trip to Japan.
    15 Sept. 1957 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's correspondence.
    8 Nov. 1957 - ALS Describes Dos Passos' current condition.
    3 Jan. 1958 - ALS
    3 Feb. 1958 - ALS
    28 Mar. 1958 - ALS
    18 Apr. 1958 - ALS
    28 May 1958 - ALS
    12 Nov. 1958 - ALS
    24 Nov. 1959 - ALS Writes about current literary activity.
    18 May 1960 - ALS Contains some views on the current international situation.
    14 Jul. 1961 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's Collected Poems, and notes history of World War I.
    21 Oct. 1961 - ALS
    11 Nov. 1961 - ALS
  - Downes, W. L., 1918-1919; 21 Letters (Box 2)
    15 Jan. 1918 - ALS These letters are from a friend serving in AEF during World War I.
    3 Mar. 1918 - ALS
    12 Apr. 1918 - ALS
    5 May 1918 - ALS
    21 May 1918 - ALS
    26 May 1918 - ALS
    28 May 1918 - ALS
    3 Jun. 1918 - ALS
    8 Jun. 1918 - ALS
    4 Jul. 1918 - ALS
    17 Jul. 1918 - ALS
    26 Jul. 1918 - ALS
    5 Aug. 1918 - ALS
    6 Sept. 1918 - ALS
    26 Oct. 1918 - ALS
    6 Nov. 1918 - ALS
    10 Nov. 1918 - ALS
    21 Nov. 1918 - ALS
    26 Nov. 1918 - ALS
    15 Mar. 1919 - ALS
    17 Mar. 1919 - ALS
  - Duke, Vernon, 1937; 1957; 1 Letter, 2 Cards (Box 2)
    15 Mar. 1937 - Signed Card. Discusses setting some of Hillyer's poetry to music.
    29 Jul. 1937 - Signed Card. Further remarks about setting some Hillyer poems to music and details Duke's current musical activity.
    21 Jan. 1957 - ALS Concerns a Duke opera based on Pushkin.
  - Eastman, Max, 1929; 1950,; 1954,; 1961; 6 Letters, 2 Cards (Box 2)
    5 May 1929 - ALS Requests information about some sonnets by e. e. cummings.
    22 Jun. 1929 - ALS Mentions current literary activity.
    28 Mar. 1950 - Signed Card.
    30 Aug. 1954 - TLS Writes about Poems of Five Decades.
    10 Sept. 1954 - Signed Card. Discusses the possibility of a Hillyer review of Poems of Five Decades.
    1 May 1961 - TLS Comments on nominees for National Institute of Arts and Letters.
    21 Jun. 1961 - TLS Mentions book of Hillyer's.
    20 Oct. 1961 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's In Pursuit of Poetry.
  - Eaton, Charles Edward, 1958; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    2 Jul. 1958 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's poetry and essays, laments of the general state of modern poetry, and details Eaton's current literary activities.
  - Eberhardt, Richard, 1940; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    5 Feb. 1940 - TLS Writes regarding Eberhardt's poetry and includes comments on other poets' activities.
  - Edmonds, Walter D., 1930; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    27 Dec. 1930 - ALS Concerns a review of an Edmonds work.
  - Eliot, T. S., 1932; undated; 1 letter and 1 Christmas card (Box 2)
    28 Oct. 1932 - TLS
    Undated - Christmas Card.
  - Engle, Paul, 1941; 1959; 3 Letters (Box 2)
    27 Dec. 1941 - TLS Regretfully refuses Hillyer's invitation to give Morris Gray Lecture at Harvard.
    14 Jan. 1959 - TLS Mentions applicant for position recommended by Hillyer and describes life of State University of Iowa; encloses poem by Engle on Robert Frost.
    16 May 1959 - TLS Encloses a book of poetry published by students of State University of Iowa.
  - Faulkner, William, 1956; 3 Letters (Box 2)
    1 Oct. 1956 - TLS Two letters under the same cover discussing plans for a meeting concerning President Eisenhower's "People-To-People Program."
    20 Nov. 1956 - TLS Further discussion of the "People-To-People Program;" with mimeographed enclosure of facetious proposals and a serious program.
  - Fessenden, Reginald, 1924; 3 Letters (Box 2)
    9 Nov. 1924 - TLS Gives some information about The Book of The Dead and talks of some of the discoveries.
    19 Nov. 1924 - TLS Invites Hillyer to tea.
    3 Dec. 1924 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's Carmus and The Hills Give Promise, and mentions Hillyer's The Coming Forth by Day.
  - Ficke, A. D., 1934; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    17 Oct. 1934 - TLS Replies to Hillyer's discussion of a person identified as "poor Ann."
  - Fitts, Dudley, 1947; 3 Letters (Box 2)
    20 Mar. 1947 - TLS Tells of the project editing Pound's Milan Cantos.
    20 Jun. 1947 - TLS Writes regarding translation of Oedipus Tyrannos.
    11 Sept. 1947 - TLS Writes about Hillyer's Poems for Music, and some essays by Hillyer on Greek literature.
  - Fitzgerald, Robert, 1957; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    17 Apr. 1957 - TLS Writes regarding translating the Odyssey.
  - Fitzhugh, Robert T., 1959; 1 Letter (Box 2)
    11 Jun. 1959 - TLS with holograph marginalia. Expresses agreement with Hillyer's Saturday Review of Literature article and suggests that Hillyer has reversed opinion on Pound since days when author was Harvard student; Hillyer denies this in marginal note.
  - Flaccus, Kimball, 1956; 1958; 5 Letters (Box 2)
    12 Aug. 1956 - TLS Mentions Flaccus' current activities
    15 Aug. 1956 - TLS and contemporary writers. Notes current literary endeavors and encloses a picture of author; also makes caustic comments on "the poobahs of modern poetry."
    12 Sept. 1956 - TLS Describes reasons for disliking Gustav Davidson's methods of running Poetry Society of America.
    14 Apr. 1958 - TLS Outlines current poetic activity.
    16 Apr. 1958 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's The Relic and Other Poems.
  - Fletcher, John Gould, 1929-1930; 2 Letters (Box 2)
    28 Nov. 1929 - ALS Reports on some of Fletcher's work and mentions some current literature.
    7 Dec. 1930 - ALS Discusses Branches of Adam and Hillyer's The Gates of the Compass.
  - Fowler, Gene, 1941-1951; 1953-1955,; 1960,; undated; 97 Letters, 1 Telegram; 2 folders (Box 2)
    Undated - ALS
    Undated - ALS Mentions enjoyment of Hillyer's work.
    Undated - ALS Requests Hillyer to criticize two chapters of unnamed book.